## Dhanusree Kodali

Software Developer

P Dallas, TX +1 (972) 946-1058 dhanusreekodali@gmail.com in www.linkedin.com/in/dhanusreek/
https://dhanu0725.github.io/my-portfolio/

#### **SUMMARY**

Skilled Software Developer with 3+ years of experience in designing, coding, testing, and deploying software applications. Proficient in Java, Python, JavaScript, and SQL. Solid background in Agile methodologies, object-oriented programming, and web development frameworks. Managed successful delivery of 2 software projects with teams of up to 8 members within stringent deadlines.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **University of North Texas**

Denton, TX

Master of Science - Computer Science

August 2021 – December 2022

Swami Ramananda Tirtha Institute of Science and Technology

Nalgonda, India

Bachelor of Technology – Computer Science and Engineering

*August 2016 – October 2020* 

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

<b>Programming Languages</b>	C, C++, Java, PHP, Python
UI/Scripting Languages	HTML5, CSS3, XML, JavaScript, Typescript, jQuery, Bootstrap, React,
	Angular, Node JS, Bash & Shell Scripting
Java Frameworks	Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring MVC, Hibernate, JPA, Spring Batch
Databases	MySQL, PostgreSQL, Mongo DB, Cassandra
Cloud Technologies	AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, Lambda EKS), Azure, Docker, Kubernetes
Build Tools/Other	Ant, Maven, Gradle, UML, Tableau, OAuth 2.0, Django
Messaging Queues & Monitoring	Apache Kafka, Splunk, SonarQube
Tools	
<b>Testing Tools &amp; Automation Tools:</b>	JUnit, Mockito, Jenkins
Version Control/Tracking tools	GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira
Operating Systems	Windows, Linux, Unix

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- AWS (Certified Developer-Associate)
- Meta (Back-End Developer)
- The Johns Hopkins University (HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for Web Developers)

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack Java Developer - Arcane Systems Inc., Temple, TX

March 2023 - June 2024

- Developed 12 cloud-native REST APIs supporting a customer-facing web application using Java, Spring Boot, and Hibernate resulting in 30% faster performance.
- Built reusable React components as part of a 6-member Agile team to enhance the client-side UI and UX for improved customer engagement.
- Developed high-performance backend modules with Core Java, expertly handling collections, multithreading, and
  exception handling, leading to a 30% enhancement in data processing speed and a 15% reduction in memory
  usage.
- Deployed Kafka to streamline message publishing and consumption, leading to a 35% reduction in data latency and efficient storage in MongoDB.
- Set up CI/CD pipelines using lenkins, and AWS deployment scripts accelerating release cycles by 40%.

• Collaborated with product owners, QAs, and designers following Agile methodologies in 2-week sprints.

## **Software Developer - Avansa IT Solutions, Cranbury, NJ**

August 2022 – December 2022

- Optimized database queries in PostgreSQL to improve application performance and reduce response times by 20%.
- Designed UI using Angular 9, and Node.js and implemented services to pull JSON data exposed through REST services along with Node Package Manager (NPM) to manage modules.
- Operated CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins with 90%+ automated unit test coverage and 85% integration test coverage, ensuring high code quality and reducing defects.
- Coordinated in over 300+ code reviews, 35 retrospectives, and daily stand-ups promoting collaboration.

# Software Engineer - Innomax IT Solutions, Hyderabad, India

August 2020 - July 2021

- Addressed with React.js components, Forms, Events, Keys, routing concepts, and React Hooks.
- Implemented a microservices architecture that improved system modularity and reduced by 65% dependencies between components.
- Enhanced RESTful API that handles over 8 million requests per day with response times under 3 milliseconds.
- Applied security measures using OAuth 2.0 to securely authenticate and authorize access.
- Incorporated Docker commands to build Docker images and deployed to AWS cloud using Amazon EKS (Elastic Kubernetes Services).
- Performed test-driven development using Mockito and JUnit for unit and production testing.

Software Engineer Intern - Innomax IT Solutions, Hyderabad, India

*May 2019 – December 2019* 

- Worked on resolving bugs and issues by analyzing the root causes by backtracking and debugging from primary reports down to the underlying logic within the backend system.
- Gained experience with Atlassian collaborative tools like Jira, and Bitbucket.

### UNIVERSITY PROJECTS

**Expense Tracker** 

*January 2022 – April 2022* 

It is a personal finance management tool with React and Java, allowing users to track income and expenses, categorize them, and visualize spending habits. Used Postgres to store transactions, categories, and user data.

**Virtual Classroom** 

*August 2022 – December 2022* 

A Virtual Classroom is an online platform where teachers and students can interact in real time, conduct live classes, share resources, and collaborate. The frontend is built with Angular, ensuring a dynamic and responsive user interface, while the backend is developed using Python, providing robust data handling and processing.

### **Multiplayer Card Game**

*August 2021 – December 2021* 

The Multiplayer Card Game is an online application where players can join, create, and play various card games in real time with others. The project focuses on building a robust backend with Python and Django to handle real-time interactions, game logic, and player management, while the frontend built with React provides a dynamic and engaging user interface.